JOSHUA BENJAMIN

256 E. Jackson St., New Holland, PA, 17557 Phone: 717.538.0866 | Email: joshuasevendavid@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshua-benjamin-046a7196/

GitHub: https://github.com/jbenj-upenn | Portfolio: https://jbenj-upenn.github.io/personal-profile-

v2020/

Summary

Front-End and Back-End Developer with a background in Linguistics and Education who seeks to use expertise in language to better communicate with app and website users. Full (MERN) stack certificate received from the University of Pennsylvania. Recently worked remotely in a group of four to develop an app that allows users to create a variety of personal goals, from professional to personal, for themselves, as well as connect with and support other users with similar goals. Looking forward to working in a collaborative environment with other developers on a variety of challenging and rewarding projects, using my professional background and experiences thus far to provide end-users of responsive apps with powerful and pleasant online experiences.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS (and various CSS frameworks like Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, etc.), JavaScript, jQuery, API client-side server calls (AJAX), HTTP calls, JSON, Node.JS and NPM packages, MySql/Sequelize, Mongo/Mongoose, ReactJS, GIT, Github, CLI

Projects

Breaking Bread

Github: https://github.com/ksmera01/Breaking-Bread

Deployed Project: https://breaking-bread-donate.herokuapp.com/

- A full-stack app designed to link individuals or organizations with hunger-related needs with individuals or organizations with the ability to meet those needs.
- In working remotely with my three team members, our roles often overlapped. I was
 primarily focused on the front-end of the project, handling appearance and
 responsiveness using Handlebars and CSS languages.

Goal Getter

Github: https://github.com/mnicolai20/GoalGetter

Deployed Project: https://goal-getters.herokuapp.com/

- A full-stack app designed to connect users with similar goals as well as simply allow users to describe and save their goals, deleting them when they have been achieved.
- Working remotely with my three team members, I handled the front-end technology using ReactJS.

Covid Activities

Github: https://github.com/jbenj-upenn/CovidActivities

Deployed Project: https://jbenj-upenn.github.io/CovidActivities/

- A front-end app designed to allow users to search APIs for new recipes to try at home or new books to read and discuss with other users.
- Working remotely with my three team members, all of our roles overlapped during this
 project, utilizing JavaScript for the most part, as well as CSS and HTML.

Experience

- Freelance Muralist/Artist, 2000-Present
- English Adjunct Professor, University of Pennsylvania, 2013-2020
- English Adjunct Professor, Drexel University, 2010-2020
- Spanish Teacher/English as a Second Language Teacher, La Academia, 2009-2010
- Spanish Teacher, Living Word Academy, 2003-2008

Education

- University of Pennsylvania/Trilogy Educational Services, 2020- received certificate
 as a full-stack computer developer. We will have covered HTML; CSS and CSS
 frameworks (e.g., Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize); JavaScript; jQuery; Web, Third-Party,
 and Server-Side APIs; NodeJs and its common packages (e.g., Express, FS); MySQL
 and Sequelize; Mongo and Mongoose; and React.
- West Chester University, 2010- West Chester, PA; earned a Master's of Arts in TESL (Teaching English as a Second Language); Cumulative GPA- 4.0/4.0
- Millersville University, 2003- Millersville, PA; earned a double major Bachelor's of Arts in English Linguistics and ESL (English as a Second Language) with a Spanish minor; Cumulative GPA- 3.54/4.0